Finding Aid for the Powell Family Papers LSC.0230
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Papers of George Harold Powell
  - Photographs
    - G. Harold Powell in his later years including a photograph of his publications. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - San Francisco Earthquake., 1906.; Negative Photographs. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Backing for Edward Weston photograph of GHP removed to #98 Weston.. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - United States Food Administration, Division of Perishable Foods., 1917-1919. (Box 11)
      [A photographic album of the personnel with some biographical information and a few autographs].
  - Memorials and Obituaries
    - Scrapbook of Obituaries., Loose-leaf notebook. (Box 11)
    - In Memoriam, G. Harold Powell., 1872-1922. (Box 11)
      [A bound volume of messages sent to Mrs. G. Harold Powell and others].
    - Clippings on the death of G. Harold Powell., 1 manila envelope. (Box 11)
    - Scrapbook on the death of G. Harold Powell. (Box 31)
      Includes clippings, photographs and correspondence.
      (Shelved at the end of the collection.)
      - G. Harold Powell, Memorial [by California Fruit Growers Exchange] Los Angeles, California., March 20, 1922.; 3 copies. (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - In Memoriam G. Harold Powell., March 1922.; Signed by Herbert Hoover. An illuminated manuscript on vellum accompanied by a letter from Mr. Hoover to Mrs. G. Harold Powel leaves. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Materials relating to the memorial tablet to G. Harold Powell placed in the U.S. Department of Agriculture building by former members of the Division of Perishable Foods, U.S. Food Administration., April 25, 1923. (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Includes an invitation to the ceremonies; a letter to Gertrude Clark Powell April 12, 1923; press release by the U.S. Department of Agriculture April 27, 1923; and newspaper clippings.
      - Presentation of Memorial Tablet of the Late George Harold Powell to the United States Department of Agriculture by the former Members of the Division of Perishable Foods of the United States Food Administration. Washington, U.S. Department of Agriculture., April 25, 1923.; 12pp. 3 copies. (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Exercises held at the Administration Building, Department of Agriculture, Washington, D.C., 3 p.m., April 25, 1923; Carbon copy typescript. 8pp. (Box 11, Folder 4)
        On the Occasion of the Presentation of the Bronze Tablet in Memory of the Late George Harold Powell. Secretary Wallace Presiding.
    - Photographs of the funeral flowers and the Memorial Tablet in the U.S. Department of Agriculture. (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - The cut used in printing the photographic reproductions of the Memorial Tablet in the U.S. Department of Agriculture. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Papers of Gertrude Clark Powell
  - Oversize # 5: Photographs, Powell, Gertrude (Clark), c., 1931.; 2 items. (Box 13)
    - Account Books, Address Books, Legal Papers, etc.
      - Account books and Odds and Ends books., 4 items. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Address books., 2 items. (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Reading List of Books and Guest book., 2 items (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Legal papers. (Box 13, Folder 4)
        Including investment certificates, Last Will and Testament, and passport.
    - Diaries, Journals, etc.
      - January-December 1893. (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - November 1893-February 1894. (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - October 1894-June 1895. (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - September 1897-December 1899. (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - January 1900-December 1903. (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - January 1904-December 1906. (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - January 1907-December 1911. (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - January 1912-December 1916. (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - January 1917-March 1919. (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - April 1919-January 1924. (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - January 1924-February 1926. (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - March-December 1926; March 1930-September 1931. (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - January-September 1929. (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - October 1931-October 1932. (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - November 1932-July 1933. (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - July 1933-June 1934. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - July 1934-December 1936. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - January 1937-October 1938. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - 1939. (Box 14, Folder 2)
        Diary of a trip to the San Francisco World's Fair.
      - March 1942-August 1954. (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - September 1945-June 1948. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - June 1948-November 1952. (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - December 1952-November 1954. (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - December 1954-June 1956. (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - June 1956-June 1957. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Publications and Writings
      - Old Commonplace Book including Gertrude Clark Powell's Poetry., 1 vol. (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Gertrude Clark Powell's Commonplace Book., 1 vol. (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Horoscopes of various persons and materials on Astrology., 2 vol. (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Rational Food Compiled by Gertrude Clark Powell., 1 vol. (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Miscellaneous writings of Gertrude Clark Powell from W.L.A., April 1928.; 3 vol. (miniatures). (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Autobiographical notes writtin during Gertrude Clark Powell's stay in France., 1931-1932. (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - A Little Tour to Vézelay. Los Angeles., 1940.; 2 copies. (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Letters to Gertrude Clark Powell and Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons., 1940-1941 and n.d. (Box 16, Folder 5)
        re A Little Tour to Vézelay.
      - The Quiet Side of Europe., Holograph manuscript with corrections. 507 leaves. (Box 16, Folder 6ab)
      - The Quiet Side of Europe. By Lawrence Clark Powell., Typescript with corrections. 267 leaves. (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - The Quiet Side of Europe. With a Memoir of the Author by her Son, Lawrence Clark Powell. (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Los Angeles., 1958.; Typescript with some corrections. 265 leaves. (Box 17)
      - Correspondence to Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons., 1958-1959. (Box 17, Folder 3)
        re The Quiet Side of Europe
      - Correspondence to Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons., 1960-1963 and n.d. (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence to various persons from Lawrence Clark Powell., 1958-1960. (Box 17, Folder 5)
        re The Quiet Side of Europe.
    - Books in Her Library
      - Boise, James Robinson
        - Four Books of Xenophon's Anabasis with Introduction, Map, Notes, Lexicon, Table of Gramatical References and Exercises, and Tables of Illustrations. New York: Appleton., 1887. (Box 18)
      - Burns, Robert
        - The Cotter's Saturday Night. With illustrations drawn by F.A. Chapman and engraved by J. Filmer. Philadelphia: Porter and Coates (Box 18)
      - Campbell, Thomas
        - Gertrude of Wyoming; or, The Pennsylvanian Cottage. With thirty-five illustrations engraved by the Brothers Dalziel. New York: Appleton., 1869. (Box 18)
        - Dew-Drops. Published by the American Tract Society, 150 Nassau Street, New York. (Box 18)
      - Higgins, Violet Moore
        - The Gingerbread Man. An Old, Old Story Retold and Illustrated by V.M. Higgins. Chicago: Albert Whitman, c., 1926. (Box 18)
      - The Iliad of Homer. Books 1-3. With an Introduction and Notes by Robert P. Keep. 6th edition. Boston: Allyn and Bacon., 1889 [c.1883]. (Box 18)
      - Root, George F.
        - First Years in Song-Land; A Singing Book for Day Schools and Juvenile Singing Classes Containing Carefully Graded Lessons and Musical Exercises... Cincinnati, Ohio: John Church., 1879. (Box 18)
      - Sheldon, E.A.
        - The Fifth Reader. New York: Scribner, Armstrong and Company, c., 1875. (Box 18)
        - Songs for My Children. With numerous illustrations. Boston: American Tract Society., 1861. (Box 18)
      - Thomas A. Kempis
        - The Limitation of Christ in Three Books. Translated from the Latin by John Payne with an introductory essay by Thomas Chalmers. New York: Collins., 1847. (Box 18)
    - Memorabilia and Photographs
      - Childhood. (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - High School Years at Buffalo High School, to 1890. (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Cornell University, Class of, 1895. (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Clippings concerning the Powell Family. (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Her Children and Grandchildren--Memorabilia. (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Her Children and Grandchildren--Photographs. (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Photographs of Gertrude Clark Powell. (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Photographs of Gertrude Clark and George Harold Powell families. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Six photograph albums of South Pasadena, Westwood, etc. (Box 19B)
    - Greeting Cards. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Pepys, Samuel. A Pepsian Pastorale [... for Gertrude C. Powell on her 75th birthday...] Los Angeles, Printed by Richard Hoffman, 1945. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence to various persons from various persons., 1945-1946 and n.d. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      re A Pepsian Pastorale.
    - Country Club Magazine., December 1930. (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Letters to Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons., 1957-1958. (Box 20, Folder 6)
      re the Death of Gertrude Clark Powell
- Papers of Harold Clark Powell
  - Publications and Writings
    - Journals--, 1918. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - 1920. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - 1921. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Journals--, 1922. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - 1924. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - 1928. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - The Culture of the Orange and Allied Fruits. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - South Africa, Central News Agency., 1930.; 355pp. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - South African Agricultural Series, no.8. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      A review appearing in the California Citrograph (May 1931) accompanies the book.
    - The Economic Importance of the Citrus Industry in South Africa. University of Pretoria., 1933.; 24pp. (Series no. 1, 24). (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Publications about Harold Clark Powell
    - Various articles and clippings. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Memorabilia and Photographs
    - Miscellaneous items including his Baby Book. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Photographs including some of his wives and children. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Memoir and Obituaries
    - Articles, newspaper clippings, and a letter to Gertrude Clark Powell from H.J. Webber, Professor of Subtropical Horticulture, Emeritus, at the University of California, Riverside. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - H. Clark Powell, 1900-1938; Memoirs of His Life and a Bibliography of His Writings. Edited by Lawrence Clark Powell. Los Angeles., 1939.; Typescript draft with corrections. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - H. Clark Powell, 1900-1938; Memoirs of His Life and a Bibliography of His Writings. Edited by Lawrence Clark Powell. Los Angeles., 1939.; Page proofs with corrections. 18pp. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, to Lawrence Clark Powell from various persons., 1939-1940. (Box 22, Folder 7)
      re the publication, H. Clark Powell, 1900-1938...
  - Diaries
    - Diaries., 1925-1929. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Horoscope for H. Clark Powell, diary for 1919, explanatory notes by LCP., 1915-1919. (Box 41, Folder 6)
- Papers of the Powell-Lawrence-Haines-Clark Families
  - The Families
    - Lawrence Family Tree. By Marian Clark Cooch., Holograph manuscript. 1 leaf (oversize). (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Haines Family Tree. By Marian Clark Cooch., Holograph manuscript. 1 leaf (oversize). (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Powell Family Tree. By Lawrence Clark Powell., Holograph manuscript. 2 leaves. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous photographs. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Fox, George. A Journal or Historical Account of the Life, Travels, Sufferings and Christian Experiences, & c. of George Fox... With a Preface by William Penn and The Testimony of Margaret Fox. Printed and sold by T. Sowle., 1694. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Photographs: the George Townsend Powell family. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Photographs: the George Townsend Powell residence at Ghent. New York. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Photographs: various members of the Powell family. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Clippings. (Box 24, Folder 4)
      re various members of the Powell family, including Elizabeth Powell Bond.
    - Bond, Elizabeth Powell
      - Words by the way. 1st. & 2nd. Series. Swarthmore, Pennsylvania. The Author., 1901. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Johnson, Emily Cooper. (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Dean Bond of Swarthmore, a Quaker humanist. Philadelphia, Lippincott (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Powell, Aaron Macy. (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Personal reminiscences of anti-slavery and other reforms and reformers. Plainfield, New Jersey, Anna Rice Powell., 1899. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - In memoriam, Aaron Macy Powell., 1900. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Thomas Powell of Westbury, Long Island., 1934.; 7 leaves. typescript (Photocopy). (Box 24, Folder 9)
      Compiled from Long Island Genealogies, by Mary Powell Bunker, pp.29-42; and History of Columbia County, New York; and family data.
- Papers of the Clark Family
  - Clark, Edgar W.
    - History and Genealogy of Samuel Clark, Sr., and His Descendants From 1636-1892 - 256 years. 2nd edition. St. Louis, Missouri: Nixon-Jones Printing Company. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - The History and Genealogy of Samuel Clark Sr.., (Typescript--Photocopy.) (Box 25, Folder 1A)
    Compiled by Rev. Edgar W. Clark... Details complete as available only on branches which have been brought up to date 1969. [April, 1970].
  - Biographical sketch of William H. Clark., 1844-1913.; Newspaper clipping with a Photocopy. (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: Clark family. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    [For additional Clark family photographs see Box 25D]
  - Beach, Lewis. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Cornwall. Newburgh, New York: E.M. Ruttenber and Son, Printers., 1873. (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Papers of the Haines Family
  - Early records of the Haines family from Clovercroft Chronicles. By Mary Rhodes Haines., Typescript. 12 leaves. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Marriage certificate of Jesse Haines and Rachel Otley., 1944.; Copy. Holograph manuscript. 15 leaves. (Box 37, Folder 2)
    Copied by Marian Clark Cooch with an accompanying letter to Lawrence Clark Powell
  - Correspondence., 1836-1892, and n.d. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Diaries. (2 copies)., 1852 1864, 1870-1872, 1877. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Album of remembrance. (Box 37, Folder 5)
    A gift to Mary Lawrence Haines from her mother, Phebe (Lawrence) Haines.
  - Haines, John Wesley, comp. (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Richard Haines and His Descendants: A Quaker Family of Burlington County, New Jersey, Since 1682., 1961.; Boyce, Virginia: Carr Publishing Company. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Notes By the Way. By Phebe (Lawrence) Haines., 1852. (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook. (Box 37, Folder 8)
    Containing material on the Haines family, particularly concerning its genealogy.
  - Photograph and drawing of Jesse Haines., 1901 and 1885.; Both are framed. (Box 37, Folder 9)
    [For additional photographs of the Haines family, see Box 25D.]
- Papers of the Lawrence Family
  - Family correspondence., 1836-1847. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Fragment of an autobiography by Phebe (Lawrence) Haines., Carbon copy typescript with notes and corrections. 2 leaves. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Description of the Lawrence Townley Estate, Great Britain. By Jesse H. Haines., Holograph manuscript. 8 leaves. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Lawrence, Thomas
    - Historical Genealogy of the Lawrence family, from Their First Landing in This Country, A.D. 1635, to the present date, July 4th, 1858. New York, Edward O. Jenkins. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Moule, Thomas
    - Heraldry of Fish; Notices of the Principal Families Bearing Fish on Their Arms. London: John Van Voorst., 1842. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook. (Box 38)
    Containing material on the Lawrence family, particularly concerning its genealogy.
- Papers of Marian Lawrence (Clark) Cooch, Sister of Gertrude (Clark) Powell
  - Correspondence of Marian (Clark) Cooch., 1886-1941. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Diplomas and memorabilia of Marian (Clark) Cooch. (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of paintings by Marian (Clark) Cooch and Mr. Martin, and newspaper clippings ragarding same. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - An Account of the Buried Treasure at Cooch's Bridge, Delaware, in 1777. By Marian (Clark) Cooch. Published in the Newark Post in Also, an article in the Newark Post in, commemorating the 50th anniversary of the newspaper's founding., 1910. 1959 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - The Cooch Family of Cooch's Bridge, New Castle County, Delaware., Carbon copy typescript, 5 leaves. (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Cooch family correspondence., and miscellaneous papers., 1952-1967 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Cooch, Mrs. Mary Evarts (Webb)
    - Ancestry and Descendants of Nancy Allyn (Foote) Webb, Rev. Edward Webb, and Joseph Wilkins Cooch. Wilmington, Delaware: Star Publishing Company., 1919. (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Photographs
    - Haines family. (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - William Henry Clark. (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Mary Lawrence (Haines) Clark. (Box 40, Folder 3)
      [For additional photographs of the Clark family, see Box 25.]
    - Cooch family. (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Marian (Clark) Cooch. (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Marian (Clark) Cooch, children and grandchildren. (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - The Cooch house and Cooch's Bridge, Delaware. (Box 40, Folder 7)
- Papers of Harold Haines Clark
  - Business Correspondence
    - Letters to various persons., 1907-1930. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Letters from various persons., 1907-1930. (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers
    - Invoices, receipts, etc. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Account book., 1896-1906. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Estate and funeral of Emma Holbrook Clark. (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Writings of Harold Haines Clark
    - Personal memorandum and note book. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Diaries--, 1931, 1950, 1951, 1953-1957, 1959, 1961. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Autobiographical sketch., 1938. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Camp Sunnyside on Lower Saranac Lake in the Adirondacks., 1903. (Box 26, Folder 9)
      A journal of the sojourn of William H. Clark... beginning February 22, 1903. Unpaged includes a map, clippings, tipped-in illustrations and correspondence.
    - A geographical notebook., May 1933-June 8, 1933. (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - A technical education at Cornell University., February 6, 1909. (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous writings. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Writings of Emma Holbrook Clark
    - A September Camp and a Short Story. (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Link-Belt Company
    - Miscellaneous
      - The Link. vol.1 (, 1926 to 1930).; 156pp. (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Photograph Album., 1913-1921. (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Scrapbook., 1915. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Publications about Harold Haines Clark Family
    - Bacon, Francis Miller
      - In Memoriam, Emma Holbrook Clark., 1879-1930.; Unleaved. (Box 28, Folder 1)
        Illustrated with a photographic portrait of Emma Holbrook Clark.
      - Harold Haines Clark. [Eulogy]., 1878-1964 (Box 28, Folder 2)
        Spoken by Lawrence Clark Powell at Memorial Services Held for Harold Haines Clark... Printed by William M. Cheny, 1964].
  - Memorabilia
    - Constitution and By-laws of the Funfbund., Corrected typescript including photographs. 43 leaves. (Box 28, Folder 3)
      Including essays by Julian C. Smith, Harold H. Clark, and A.E. Retermann describing their life and friendship as members of the Class of 1900, Cornell University.
    - Cornelliana. A Scrapbook. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Photographs
    - Harold Haines Clark Family including a photograph of O.T. Holbrook. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - A Photograph Album. (Box 29)
    - Emma Holbrook Clark., A Photographic Album., 1908-1930 (Box 29)
    - Photographs, An Album. (Box 29)
- Oversize Packages
  - Papers of George Harold Powell
    - Scrapbook., 1904-1909. (Box 30 (oversize))
    - Scrapbook. (Box 31)
      On the death of George Harold Powell, including clippings, photographs, and correspondence.
  - Bible. (Box 32)
    Given to Thomas Lawrence by his father, Daniel Lawrence.
  - Diaries., 1912-1963. (Box 36)
    Mainly short, intermittent notations on everyday affairs.
  - Photographs; Poueu, Gertrude (Clark), c. (2)., 1931. (Box 30)
- Research Material
  - History and Genealogies of the Powells in America., 1935.; Photocopy. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    (Box not full)